CHRISTOPHER SIMMONDS

Tucson, AZ

Phone: 520-256-6124 | Email: christophersimmonds551@gmail.com **LinkedIn**: https://www.linkedin.com/in/christopher-simmonds **GitHub**: https://github.com/Christoph551

Portfolio: https://github.com/Christoph551/Simmonds-React-Portfolio

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with a background in Telecommunications and a strong desire to continue professional development. Effective at producing results in both a group setting or working alone. Experience in a work-from-home environment. Known for being a team player with strong attention to detail and having effective communication skills.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Technical Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node, JQuery, SQL, MongoDB, Sequelize, Mongoose, Express, CSS Frameworks (Bootstrap, MUI, etc...), Git Flow, React

PROJECTS

Gauntlet | github.com/awalker2411/Gauntlet | thegauntlet.herokuapp.com

- Final project in UofA Bootcamp with one other person. This was to implement what we had learned throughout the bootcamp.
- Front-end responsibilities: Styling, routing, building pages for each view, mobile responsiveness
- Back-end responsibilities: Authentication, skeleton file structure to spin up local server
- REACT, React-Bootstrap, React-Dom, React-Dom-Router, JWT, Bcrypt, Apollo-Client

Couch Potato Assistant | *christoph551.github.io/Couch-Potato-Assistant/* | *github.com/Christoph551/Couch-Potato-Assistant*

- First project in the UofA Bootcamp. Simple application that uses 2 APIs to gather movie data and return it to the user after a search.
- Responsible for page layout, favicon/logo, styling, mobile responsiveness.
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript

E-Commerce Backendt | *github.com/Christoph551/E-Commerce-Backend* | <u>Demonstration Video of Backend Code</u>

- A project to build backend logic for an E-Commerce platform.
- Responsible for building database and establishing routes for CRUD methods
- Node, Express, SQL and Sequelize

EXPERIENCE

Operations Manager GSW Telecom

02/2022 - 10/2022

Tucson, AZ

Manager of Low-Voltage Operations with a team of 4 people. Responsible for reviewing construction blueprints, estimating, building project timeline, and allocating resources. Acted as Lead field technician in implementing structured cabling solutions.

Key Accomplishments:

- Successfully completed implementation for a large office building of over 300 cables. Approximately \$30,000 of revenue brought in, along with a relationship for future business.
- Received e-QIP clearance to work onsite government facilities.
- Maintained contract with government entity by providing first class technical support onsite.

Field Service Manager Dish Network

04/2021 – 02/2022

Tucson, AZ

Responsible for day to day operations with a team of 15 technicians throughout southern Arizona. Conducted performance reviews and ongoing field training. Onboarded new hire technicians and facilitated training in the local office and in the field.

Key Accomplishments:

- Drove technicians to strive for the best in key metrics: Sales, Net Promoter Score, maintaining low repair percentages, and Productivity.
- Recognized for supporting the team in the field when work volume was higher than available technicians.

Quality Assurance Specialist Dish Network

02/2019 - 04/2021

Tucson, AZ

Provided high-level of professionalism and expertise for escalated customers. Performed routine audits on processes, fleet services and inventory. Document technicians progress to gather data to identify trends for productivity.

Key Accomplishments:

- Started as a temporary position but received an invitation to become QAS for southern Arizona
- Received Teamwork Award for participating in early stages of MVDDS.

Satellite Technician Dish Network 01/2017 - 02/2019

Tucson, AZ

Install and service satellite television and internet systems. Provided in-home sales consultations and performed installation of a variety of smart home products and services.

Key Accomplishments:

- Promoted to level 4 technician within 2 years
- Achieved certifications for Sears, HughesNet, ViaSat and Amazon

EDUCATION

Boot Camp Certificate: University of Arizona, Tucson, AZ

A 12-week intensive program focused on gaining a large variety of technical programming skills. The nature of this accelerated program was challenging and quite fulfilling.

Fire Science/EMT Basic Certification: Pima Community College, Tucson, AZ Completed Fire Academy and became EMT certified.

High School Diploma: Sahuarita High School, Sahuarita, AZ